<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://aeriumsolutions.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://aeriumsolutions.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-07T21:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://aeriumsolutions.com/</id><title type="html">Aerium Solutions</title><subtitle>UAV data collection, reporting, and environmental monitoring service</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Earthack 2017- CO2 Drone</title><link href="http://aeriumsolutions.com/markdown-syntax/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Earthack 2017- CO2 Drone" /><published>2017-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://aeriumsolutions.com/markdown-syntax</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aeriumsolutions.com/markdown-syntax/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;earthack-2017&quot;&gt;Earthack 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hackathon is a competition in which teams are given 36 hours to build/code a project on site. We did just that. Before this competition, we had all only seen each other passing by in hallways at UNT, but we left a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together we came up with the idea of a C02 sensing drone that we could control autonomously and collect gas data throughout Dallas. Currently, Dallas only has two stationary CO2 sensors that are in charge of the city as a whole. We wanted to implement a way that would record the exact locations of high emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the 36 hours, we built and programmed the drone and sensor systems. We were unable to test our flight because we were in a no-flight dronw. However, we ended up getting through the first round and presenting in the finals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We placed third overall with our CO2 drone, but that was not enough for us. We began to improve and refine our idea with the help of Michael Dwinnell, turning it into a marketable service hence Aerium Solutions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements-since-earthack&quot;&gt;Improvements since Earthack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Earthack, we have stepped up our game. No longer is this a project, but our baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our drone currently has autonomous flight via bluetooth, real-time updating of data collection, live video streaming, and more! It is adabtable and expandable to fit almost any needs. We plan on continuing to improve this idea and help the Earth cut down on emissions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">how Aerium Solutions came to be...</summary></entry></feed>